Peter E. Lynch Railroad Collection
© 2008 University of Connecticut
Peter E. Lynch Railroad Collection.
1870, 1910-1969.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
0.5 linear feet.
The Peter E. Lynch Railroad Collection consists of materials almost exclusively associated with the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad (a.k.a. New Haven Railroad), including timetables, arranged package car service lists, and train order forms. Also includes a Western Maryland Railroad mortgage bond (1870) and a Penn Central timetable (1969).
MSS20030099
Biography
Peter E. Lynch, born on October 23, 1945, graduated from Brown University and received an MBA from Rutgers University. He worked in management positions for the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, Penn Central, Conrail, and the Housatonic Railroad, and later as a railroad consultant. He was the author of New Haven Railroad (St. Paul, MN: MBI, 2003) and Penn Central Railroad (St. Paul, MN: MBI, 2004).
Peter E. Lynch died on June 14, 2011, in Worcester, Massachusetts.
Scope and Content
Unless otherwise noted the collection consists of materials associated with the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad (a.k.a. New Haven Railroad), including timetables, arranged package car service lists, and train order forms. Also includes a Western Maryland Railroad mortgage bond (1870) and a Penn Central timetable (1969).
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of southern New England railroad records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Arrangement
The materials were arranged in chronological order.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Peter E. Lynch
Organizations:
New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Company.; Western Maryland Railroad Company.; Penn Central Transportation Company.
Document Types:
Publications.; Administrative Records.; Drawings.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The materials were collected and held by Mr. Lynch prior to their donation to Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries.
Acquisition Information
The records were donated by Mr. Peter E. Lynch in 2003.
Detailed Description
- Collection
  - Western Maryland Railroad mortgage bond, 1870 (Box 1:1)
  - Instructions for train load for engines and engines loading, 1905 (Box 1:2)
  - New Haven Railroad Midland Division timetable supplements, 1910 (Box 1:3)
  - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Engineermen's Magazine, 1922 (Box 1:4)
  - New Haven Railroad timetable, west of New London and Willimantic, 1924 (Box 1:5)
  - Arranged Package Service Car booklets (showing arrangement for handling less than car load freight by rail and highway truck), 1931-1935 (Box 1:6)
  - Painting diagram for EP-5 370 locomotives (PP-8844580), 1954 (Box 2)
  - New Haven Railroad Shoreline Route timetable, 1959 (Box 1:7)
  - Train orders, from Kingston, Rhode Island, 1959 (Box 1:8)
  - Travel guide and menu, 1961 (Box 1:9)
  - Typescript draft of "Poughkeepsie Gateway" by D.M. McLaughlin, 1968 (Box 1:10)
  - Penn Central, New Haven region, employees timetable (February 2, 1969), 1969 (Box 1:11)
  - Drawings for stations in Bethel, Connecticut, Meriden, Connecticut, New Britain, Connecticut, Westchester, Connecticut, Pelham, New York, and Westerly, Rhode Island, 1976-1977, 1993 (Box 1:12)